So now you have a small neural network.
It's not particularly deep,
just 2 layers.
You can make it bigger,
more complex by increasing the size of
that hidden layer in the middle, but
it turns out that increasing this H is
not particularly efficient in general.
You need to make it very, very big,
and then it gets really hard to train.
This is where the central idea of
deep learning comes into play,
instead you can also add more layers and
make your model deeper.
There are lots of good
reasons to do that.
One is parameter efficiency.
You can typically get much more
performance with pure parameters by
going deeper, rather than wider.
Another one is that a lot
of natural phenomena,
that you might be interested in,
tend to have a hierarchical structure
which deep models naturally capture.
If you poke at a model for images, for
example, and
visualize what the model learns
you'll often find very simple things at
the lowest layers, like lines or edges.
Once you move up,
you tend to see more complicated
things like geometric shapes.
Go further up, and you start
seeing things like objects, faces.
This is very powerful, because
the model structure matches the kind
of abstractions that you might
expect to see in your data, and
as a result the model has
an easier time learning them.
[BLANK_AUDIO]