The first way we prevent over fitting,
is by looking at the performance
on our validation set.
And stopping to train,
as soon as we stop improving.
It's called early termination,
and it's still the best way to
prevent your network from over
optimizing on the training set.
Another way is to apply regularization.
Regularizing means applying artificial
constraints on your network,
that implicitly reduce
the number of free parameters.
While not making it more
difficult to optimize.
In the skinny jeans analogy,
think stretch pants.
They fit just as well, but
because they're flexible,
they don't make things harder to fit in.
The stretch pants of deep learning
are called L2 Regularization.
The idea is to add another term to
the loss, which penalizes large weights.
It's typically achieved by adding the L2
norm of your weights to the loss,
multiplied by a small constant.
And yes, yet another hyper parameter
to tune in, sorry about that