There's another important technique for
regularization
that only emerged relatively
recently and works amazingly well.
It also looks insane the first
time you see it, so bear with me.
It's called Dropout.
Dropout works like this.
Imagine that you have one layer
that connects to another layer.
The values that go from one layer to
the next are often called activations.
Now take those activations and
randomly, for every example you train
your network on, set half of them to 0.
Completely and randomly, you basically
take half of the data that's flowing
through your network, and
just destroy it and then randomly again.
If that does not sound crazy to you,
then you might qualify to become
a student of Geoffrey Hinton,
who pioneered the technique.
So what happens with dropout?
Your network can never rely on any
given activation to be present,
because they might be
squashed at any given moment.
So it is forced to learn
a redundant representation for
everything to make sure that at least
some of the information remains.
It's like a game of whack-a-mole.
One activations get smashed,
but there is always one or
more that do the same job.
And that don't get killed.
So, everything remains fine at the end.
Forcing your network to learn redundant
representations might sound very
inefficient.
But in practice, it makes things more
robust, and prevents over fitting.
It also makes your network act as if
taking the consensus over an ensemble of
networks, which is always a good
way to improve performance.
Dropout is one of the most important
techniques to emerge in the last few
years.
If Dropout doesn't work for
you, you should probably
be using a bigger network.