Because we're lazy engineers,
we're going to take something that works-
our logistic classifier and do the minimal amount of change to make it nonlinear.
We're going to construct our new function in the simplest way that we can think of.
Instead of having a single matrix multiply as our classifier,
we're going to insert a ReLU right in the middle.
We now have two matrices,
one going from the inputs to the ReLUs
and another one connecting the ReLUs to the classifier.
We've solved two of our problems.
Our function is now nonlinear,
thanks to the ReLU in the middle,
and we now have a new knob that we can tune this number H
which corresponds to the number of ReLU units that we have in the classifier.
We can make it as big as we want.
Congratulations you've built your first neural network.