The work we just did, building and
training a multi-layer
convolutional neural network,
would have taken hundreds of lines
of code just a few years ago.
&gt;&gt; That's right.
As deep neural networks become
increasingly important to everything
from self driving cars to voice
recognition, new libraries are making it
much easier to use deep learning
to solve real problems.
&gt;&gt; Next up, you are going to learn
how to take networks that have
already been trained and fine tune
them to accelerate your own work.
This is called transfer learning.
&gt;&gt; Transfer learning is
a standard tool in deep learning.
It can really reduce your training
time and improve your results.
&gt;&gt; See you soon.