Your job is to teach the car
how to drive itself.
And in order to do that you're going to
need to teach the car how to perceive
the world around it.
Now when I drive I use my eyes
to figure out how fast to go and
where the lane lines are and
where to turn.
A car doesn't have eyes, but in a
self-driving car we can use cameras and
other sensors to achieve
a similar function.
&gt;&gt; That's right, so
let's think about what those cameras
are seeing as we drive down the road.
You and I can see where the lane
lines are automatically, but
we need to teach the car how to do that.
So your goal in this first module,
is to write code to identify and
track the position of the lane
lines in a series of images.
&gt;&gt; And in the project at
the end of this first module,
you're going to use image analysis
techniques to do exactly that.
So let's start really high level.
Here's a picture of a stretch
of wide open highway.
What kinds of features do
you think would be helpful
to figure out where the lane
lines are in this image?