Looking at a grey scale image,
I see bright points, dark points, and
all the grey in between.
Rapid changes in brightness
are where we find the edges.
Our image is just a mathematical
function of x and y so
we can perform mathematical operations
on it, just like any other function.
For example, we can take its derivative,
which is just a measure of
change of this function.
A small derivative means small change.
Big derivative, big chance.
Images are two-dimensional so
it makes sense to take the derivative
with respect to x and y simultaneously.
This is called the gradient and
in computing it, we're measuring how
fast pixel values are changing at each
point in an image and in which direction
they are changing most rapidly.
Computing the gradient
gives us thick edges.
With the Canny algorithm we will
thin out these edges to find just
the individual pixels that
follow the strongest gradients.
We'll then extend those strong edges
to include pixels all the way down to
a lower threshold that we defined
when calling the Canny function.