The name Canny refers to John F Canny
who developed this edge detection
algorithm in 1986.
With edge detection,
the goal is to identify the boundaries
of an object in an image.
So to do that, first,
I'll convert to grayscale.
[SOUND] All right and next,
I'll compute the gradient.
[SOUND] Nice, okay.
So now, you're looking at the gradient
of my world, where the brightness of
each pixel corresponds to the strength
of the gradient at that point.
We're going to find edges by tracing out
the pixels that follow the strongest
gradients.
All right, but the gradient world's a
little scary, so let's go back to color.
[SOUND] By identifying edges,
we can more easily detect
objects by their shape.
So what exactly is an edge?
Let's first get some intuition by
having a look at the parameters for
the open CV Canny function.
You'll call it like this.
In this case, I'm applying the Canny
function to an image called gray and
the output will be another image called,
edges.
Low_threshold and
high_threshold determine how strong
the edges must be to be detected.
You can think of the strength of an edge
as being defined by how different
the values are in adjacent
pixels in the image.
Really just the strength
of the gradient.
Next, I'll show you how that works so
that you have a clear picture of what's
going on under the hood when you use the
Canny edge detection method in OpenCV.