Okay so
now I've taken a grayscaled image, and
using edge detection, turned it
into an image full of dots, but
only the dots that represent
edges in the original image.
Now let's connect the dots.
I could connect the dots to look for
any kind of shape in my image, but
in this case I'm looking for lines.
To find lines I need to first
adopt a model of a line, and
then fit that model to the assortment
of dots in my edge detected image.
Keeping in mind that my image
is just a function of x and y,
I can use the old familiar
equation of a line y = mx + b.
In this case, my model includes
two parameters, m and b.
In Image Space,
a line is plotted as x versus y.
But in parameter space,
which we will call Hough Space,
I can represent that same
line as m versus b instead.
The Hough transform is just
the conversion from Image Space
to Hough Space.
So the characterization
of a line in Image Space,
will be a single point at
the position mb in Hough Space.