So our strategy to find lines in
image space will be to look for
intersecting lines in Hough space.
We do this by dividing up our
Hough space into a grid, and
define intersecting lines as all lines
passing through a given grid cell.
To do this, I'll first run
the Canny edge detection algorithm
to find all points associated
with edges in my image.
I can then consider every point in this
edge-detected image as a line in Hough
space.
And where many lines in Hough space
intersect, I declare I have found
a collection of points that
describe a line in image space.
We have a problem, though.
Vertical lines have infinite
slope in MB representation,
so we need a new parameterization.
Let's redefine our line
in polar coordinates.
Now the variable rho describes
the perpendicular distance of the line
from the origin.
And theta is the angle of
the line away from horizontal.
Now each point in image space
corresponds to a sine curve in
Hough space.
If we take a whole line of points,
it translates into a whole bunch
of sine curves in Hough space.
And again,
the intersection of those sine curves
in theta rho space gives
the parameterization of the line.