Great job so far.
In this lesson, you've used image
analysis techniques like canny
edge detection and huff transforms
to find lane lines in images.
These are the exact same techniques
that you're going to need for
the first project.
So, Ryan, what will students be
doing for the first project?
&gt;&gt; Well, your goal, in this first
project, is to write a software pipeline
to identify and track the position
of the lane lines in a video stream.
That might sound complicated,
but don't worry, you can do it.
A video is really just
a series of images.
So you already have the tools
you need to do this project.
&gt;&gt; Awesome.
This project is your first step toward
becoming a real self-driving car
engineer.
And, in fact, this was one of my first
projects when I was learning to become
a self-driving car engineer.
So let's get to it.