For starters, let's try finding
the lane lines using color.
The lane lines are white, so how do we
select the white pixels in an image?
To select a color, we first need to
think about what color actually means in
the case of digital images.
In this case, it means that our image
is actually made up of a stack of
three images, one each for
red, green, and blue.
These images are sometimes
called color channels.
Each of these color channels contains
pixels whose values range from 0 to 255,
where 0 is the darkest possible value,
and 255 is the brightest possible value.
If 0 is dark and 255 is bright,
what color would represent pure white in
our combined red, green, and blue image?