When we talk about computer vision,
we're literally talking about using
algorithms to let a computer
see the world like we see it.
Full of depth, and color,
and shapes, and meaning.
Computer vision is
a really broad field and
right now we're just going to
focus on a few features.
Later in the nanodegree program,
we'll be getting much more in depth with
the tools and techniques used in
computer vision for self driving cars.
&gt;&gt; At this point we'll introduce you to
two powerful techniques that you'll use
for your first project where you'll be
identifying the lane lines in an image
of the road.
The first technique we'll look
at is Canny Edge Detection.
So let's give it a go.