I hope you enjoyed learning about
neural networks and convolutions.
So far you've been learning about deep
neural networks at the conceptual level,
and applying these techniques to
a range of image classification tasks.
In the next project you are going
to return to autonomous driving.
That's right, next you are going
to build a deep neural network
to classify traffic signs.
Your network should be able to take
an image and decide if it's a stop sign,
a yield sign, a different type of sign,
or maybe no sign at all.
&gt;&gt; This will be a terrific portfolio
project to demonstrate for
employers your hands-on practical
experience with deep neural network.