Now that the Jupyter notebook is up and running,
you can use it to classify traffic signs.
First, reset the kernel and clear the output to ensure you have a fresh start.
Next, clear the cell that loads
the MNIST data and replace it with code to load the traffic sign data.
You can find that code in the notebook for the traffic sign classifier project.
You should also delete the code that pads the images since
the traffic sign images are already 32x32 pixels.
One problem to solve though is that
the traffic sign data does not come with a validation set.
You can use the train test split function in
the sklearn library though to slice off a validation set from the training set.
You can allocate as much of the training set as you want,
20% is a good rule of thumb.
Now, you can visualize an image from the dataset but remember that
the traffic sign images are in color not grayscale like the MNIST images.
It's worth looking in the GitHub repo to compare the image label to
the CSV file that matches numeric labels to text descriptions.
In this case, the numeric label is 35
which corresponds to a head only which looks correct.
You can proceed to preprocess the data and set up TensorFlow just as we did for MNIST.
You'll have to make a few changes to the LeNet architecture though.
First, remember that the traffic sign images are in color,
not grayscale so the input depth should be three to match the three RGB color channels.
The new input depth won't affect the rest of the network architecture.
Also, if the output layer
the traffic sign classifier has 43 classes where is MNIST only had 10,
so you'll have to change that.
When you set up the TensorFlow placeholders,
you'll have to update the input and output
shapes again to match the shapes of the new dataset.
Training the network should be the same as well.
So let's run it and see how it does.
96% validation accuracy.
That's pretty good for the first shot.
Remember, don't run the test set until you're done
tuning the model and you're ready to stop training and submit the project.
For now, remember to stop or terminate
your AWS instance so that AWS stops billing you for it.
You don't want to leave your instance on and forget about it.
Otherwise, you'll wind up with a huge bill.
If you select, stop the instance will shut down but you can run it again later.
AWS will stop charging you for running
the instance but there will still be some small charges for data storage.
If you select terminate,
AWS will completely delete your instance.
So before you terminate,
make sure to download any data that you want to save.
Once you terminated instance,
all charges for it will cease.
So, looking at where to go next what could you do to further improve this model?
There are several broad categories,
you could experiment with different network architectures,
or just change the dimensions of the LeNet layers.
You could add regularization features like drop out or L2
regularization to make sure the network doesn't overfit the training data.
You could tune the hyperparameters.
You could improve the data pre-processing with
steps like normalization and setting a zero mean.
You could even augment the training data by
rotating or shifting images or by changing colors.
There are a lot of fun experiments you can run on this network so give it
a shot and see how well you can do. Good luck.