The LeNet lab from the convolutional neural networks lesson is
a great starting point for building a network to classify traffic signs.
But before you adapt LeNet for the project,
let's walk through the lab solution and review what happens on each line.
This first cell in the Jupyter notebook shows
the original drawing of the LeNet architecture from Yan LeCun's 1998 journal article.
The network takes a 32x32 images input.
Then, that image goes through a convolutional layer,
C1, followed by a subsampling layer, S2.
Since LeNet was originally designed,
subsampling layers have mostly given way to what we now
call pooling layers which is actually what we use in this lab.
Then there's another sequence of convolutional layer,
C3, followed by a pooling layer, S4.
Finally, there are three fully connected layers including the output layer at the end.
That's the architecture of LeNet.
The rest of the notebook implements this architecture in TensorFlow.