In this code cell,
we set up another pipeline,
this time for evaluating the model.
The training pipeline we just set up is what trains the model,
but the evaluation pipeline we create here will evaluate how good the model is.
The first step in this pipeline is to measure whether a given prediction is
correct by comparing the logit prediction to the one-hot encoded ground truth label.
The second step in the pipeline is to calculate
the model's overall accuracy by averaging the individual prediction accuracies.
These two lines are the entire evaluation pipeline.
But in order to run this evaluation pipeline,
we have to build an evaluate function.
This function takes a dataset as input,
sets some initial variables,
and then batches the dataset and runs it through the evaluation pipeline.
The evaluate function averages the accuracy of
each batch to calculate the total accuracy of the model.