Great! Now that everything else is set up,
we can build a function to train and validate our model.
First, we create the TensorFlow session and initialize the variables.
We train over whatever number of epochs has been set in the EPOCHS hyperparameter.
At the beginning of each epoch,
we shuffle our training data to ensure that
our training isn't biased by the order of the images.
Then, we break our training data into batches and train the model on each batch.
At the end of each epoch,
we evaluate the model on our validation data.
Once we have completely trained the model, we save it.
That way, we can load it up later and modify
it or evaluate the model on our test dataset.
As we train the model,
we see that the validation accuracy starts off really high and stays there.
Partly, this is the result of a powerful convolutional network architecture like LeNet,
and partly, this is because we've already chosen good hyperparameters.
When you experiment with your own models,
you'll probably have to spend a fair bit of time
tuning the hyperparameters to give the best results.