Now that you've seen what
a simple covnet looks like,
there are many things that
we can do to improve it.
We're going to talk about three of them,
pooling, 1x1 convolutions, and
something a bit more advanced
called the inception architecture.
The first improvement is a better way to
reduce the spatial extent of your future
maps in the convolutional pyramid.
Until now, we've used striding to shift
the filters by a few pixels each time
and reduce the feature map size.
This is a very aggressive
way to down sample an image.
It removes a lot of information.
What if instead of skipping
one in every two convolutions,
we still run with a very small stride,
say for example, one but
then took all the convolutions in
a neighborhood and combine them somehow?
That operation is called pooling, and
there are a few ways to go about it.
The most common is the max pooling.
At every point of on the feature map,
look at a small neighborhood around
that point and compute the maximum
of all the responses around it.
There are some advantages
to using max pooling.
First, it doesn't add to
your number of parameters,
so you don't risk
an increase in over fitting.
Second, it simply often
yields a more accurate model.
However, since the convolutions that
went below run at lower stride,
the muddle then becomes a lot
more expensive to compute.
And now, you have even more
hyper parameters to worry about,
the pooling region size and
the pooling stride.
And no, they don't have to be the same.
A very typical architecture for a covnet
is a few layers alternating convolutions
and max pooling, followed by a few
fully connected layers at the top.
The first famous model to use
this architecture was Lenet-5
designed by Yan Lecun to do
character recogniztion back in 1998.
Modern convolutional networks,
such as AlexNet, which famously won
the competitive ImagNnet object
recognition challengei n 2012,
used the same architecture
with a few wrinkles.
Another notable form of
pooling is average pooling.
Instead of taking the max,
just take an average over the window
of pixels around a specific location.
It's a little bit like providing
a blurred low resolution view of
the feature map below.
We're going to take
advantage of that shortly.