Let's talk about Convolutional Networks,
or CovNets.
CovNets are neural networks that
share their parameters across space.
Imagine you have an image.
It can be represented as a flat pancake.
It has a width, a height, and
because you typically have red, green,
and blue channels, it also has a depth.
In this instance, depth is three.
That's your input.
Now, imagine taking a small
patch of this image, and
running a tiny neural network on it,
with say, K outputs.
Let's represent those outputs
vertically in a tiny column like this.
Now, let's slide that little
neural network across the image
without changing the weights.
Just slide across invertically like
we're painting it with a brush.
On the output,
we've drawn another image.
It's got a different width,
a different height.
And more importantly,
it's got a different depth.
Instead of just R,G, and B, now,
you have an output that's got
many colored channels, K of them.
This operation is
called the convolution.
If your patch size were
the size of the whole image,
it would be no different than
the regular layer of a neural network.
But because we have this small patch
instead, we have many fewer weights and
they are shared across space.
A covenant is going to basically be
a deep network where instead of having
stacks of matrix multiply layers, we're
going to have stacks of convolutions.
The general idea is that
they will form a pyramid.
At the bottom, you have this big image,
but very shallow just R, G, and B.
You're going to apply convolutions that
are going to progressively squeeze
the spacial dimensions while
increasing the depth which corresponds
roughly to the semantic complexity
of your representation.
At the top, you can put your classifier.
You have a representation where
all this spacial information has
been squeezed out, and only parameters
that map to content of the image remain.
So that’s the general idea.
If you're going to implement this, there
are lots of little details to get right,
and a fair bit of lingo to get used too.
You've met the concept of Patch and
Depth.
Patches are sometimes called Kernels.
Each pancake in your stack
is called a feature map.
Here, you're mapping three
feature maps to K feature maps.
Another term that you
need to know is stride.
It's the number of pixels, so
that you're shifting each
time you move your filter.
The stride of one makes the output
roughly the same size as the input.
A stride of two means
it's about half the size.
I say roughly because it depends a bit
about what you do at the edge of your
image.
Either you don't go pass the edge, and
it's often called valid
padding as a shortcut.
Or you go off the edge and pad with
zeros in such a way that the output
map size is exactly the same
size as the input map.
That is often called same
padding as a shortcut.