If you're using the so
called same padding in a stride of 1,
the output width and
height are the same as the input.
We just add zeros to the input
image to make the sizes match.
If you use th so
called valid padding in a stride of one,
then there is no padding at all.
So if you want to fit your little filter
on the input image without doing and
padding, you're going to
have to remove one row and
one column of the image on each side.
So you're left with 26 features in
each of the maps at the output.
If in addition you use a stride of two,
then you only get half as many outputs
So, 13 in width and 13 in height.
In all cases,
the output depth isn't changed.