That's it, you can build
a simple conv net with just this.
Stack up your convolutions
which thankfully you don't
have to implement yourselves.
Then use triads to reduce
the dimensionality and
increase the depth of your
network layer after layer.
And once you have a deep and
narrow presentation, connect
the whole thing to a few regular,
fully connected layers, and
you're ready to train your classifier.
You might wonder what happens
to training and to chain rule,
in particular,
when you use shared weights like this.
Nothing really happens,
the math just works.
You just add up the derivatives for
all the possible locations on the image.