[SOUND]
&gt;&gt; Here are my colleagues,
David and Ryan.
David used to work at Ford as a engineer
before he joined as an instructor.
And Ryan is a recovering astrophysicist,
who was looking for outer space,
couldn't find them and
joined us as an instructor here at.
&gt;&gt; Awesome, thanks Sebastian.
&gt;&gt; So the most exciting part of this
course is that at the end of the course
you'll be able to put your own
code on a real self driving car.
In fact,
it's that car right there behind us.
&gt;&gt; That's right, so
welcome to the program.
You and I are going to be learning
together to write code to drive a car.
We're going to have David and
Sebastian looking after us.
And we will be bringing in industry
experts to join us in the class room as
well.
&gt;&gt; All right.