Self-driving car engineers today use
two distinct approaches to autonomous
development, a robotics approach,
and a deep learning approach.
The robotics approach fuses output from
a suite of sensors to directly measure
the vehicle's surroundings,
and then navigate accordingly.
Self-driving car engineers
have been working on and
perfecting the robotics approach for
many years.
&gt;&gt; More recently, engineering teams
have begun to use deep learning
as a different approach to
developing autonomous vehicles.
Deep neural networks allow self-driving
cars to learn how to drive
by mimicking human driving behavior.
Both the robotics and deep learning
methods are actively being pursued today
in the development of self-driving cars.
&gt;&gt; So in this Nanodegree program,
you'll be working with both approaches.
That way you, as an engineer,
will be prepared to work anywhere.
By the end of this program you'll
be teaming up with other students
to actually write both robotics and
deep learning code to control
a real self-driving car.
Pretty cool.
&gt;&gt; Along the way you'll work through
several modules, with each one focusing
on a different layer of
the self-driving car technology stack.
And after each module,
you'll build a project to
demonstrate what you've learned.
And you'll get real human
feedback on your work.
This first module that you're
going through now is smaller and
should only take a week or
so to complete.
Later modules will be longer and
may take up to a month.
In addition to receiving human
feedback on your projects,
you'll also have access to the forums,
where you can ask questions and
get to know your fellow students.
And of course,
our team is here to help you succeed, so
be sure to reach out and keep in touch.