Our very first project in
the Self-Driving Car Nanodegree will be
to find lane markings.
Why is that important?
Well, I can tell you,
if you can't find lane markings,
you will have no clue where to drive.
You probably don't pay
much attention to them.
But as a self-driving car engineer,
they become your best friend.
They tell you a lot
as to where to drive.
Behavioral cloning means that our
learning program will copy and clone
human behavior, that is, our steering
actions and brake and gas actions.
And you get a chance
to try it on your own.
When we train people, we don't train
them by giving them the rules.
We train them by letting
them learn from examples.
So in this unit,
you're going to apply neural networks,
deep learning to camera images.
And do some of the very things that
a self-driving car ought to do right.
What is computer vision?
When you and I drive a car,
we use our eyes more than any other
organ to understand what to do.
Computer vision, this gives
the same capability into computers.
It uses cameras, and we learn how to
extract things, like lane markings and
other vehicles, out of camera images.
It's a lot of fun.
[MUSIC]
And we're really excited to get
into the world of sensor fusion.
What is sensor fusion?
It is the science how to integrate
different types of sensors.
Self-driving cars have things like
LIDARs, and they have radars, and
also cameras.
And they have internal sensors called
gyroscopes, inertial measurement units.
Sensor fusion is the science how to come
up with a single coherent picture based
on these different modalities.
Localization is the simple question,
where, relative to the world, is a car?
And it's important because, as you're
going to see, you're going to build maps
of the environment with lots
of detailed information.
Some of which might even
be invisible to the robot,
like where are the danger zones?
Where do pedestrians typically cross?
And to make sense of those maps, the bot
must know where is road from the map.
And the alignment of the sensor data,
the current position to a map,
that's what's called localization.
So now we're entering the fascinating
world of what's called control.
In technical terms,
what a controller does,
it's a computer program that steers
your wheels, your gas pedal,
your brake pedal, so
as to meet a given objective.
So for example, if your objective is
to stay centered in the road, and
you start driving, and
your car veers a little bit to the left,
your controller is
the unit that decides,
okay, we compensate with a slight,
right turn of the steering wheel.
That might sound trivial, but
it's really easy to screw it up.
[MUSIC]
Path planning is designs of how to
find a valid sequence of steps or
actions in a maze.
When you are stuck in Manhattan,
for example,
and you want to cross the city,
you have to find a plan, a sequence
of streets you want to go down to
make it all the way to the other end.
A path-planning
algorithm is an algorithm
that finds that sequence of actions for
you.
We can apply it to city navigation.
We can also apply it to parking lot
navigation, in order, for example,
to cross a parking lot.
[MUSIC]
[SOUND] So now we are ready for the most
fascinating part of this nanodegree.
We will take your code onto a physical
car and drive it around in California.
Sound scary?
Yes, I'm slightly scared,
but I'm also really excited.
Because there's no great nanodegree
that would be complete without actually
writing final actual software,
actually cars.
So let's do it.