We're here with Kirsten from
the Udacity careers team.
Kirsten and her team will be providing
you with career support throughout
the program in your effort to find
a job in the self driving car industry.
They'll help to ensure your application
materials are polished, you're ready for
interviews and you're connected
to employers in the field.
We'll also be taking you behind the
scenes at top auto manufacturers to get
an idea of what they're looking for
and how the hiring process works.
&gt;&gt; In addition to this course, we're
working with more than a dozen hiring
partners about our
leaders in this field,
such as Mercedes Benz, nVidia,
BMW, Otto, Di Di, and many more.
We're also working with
software companies,
radar and lidar manufacturers, and
many others that are searching for
top talent in this growing field.
Having hiring partners like these means
that you, as a student, have direct and
preferential exposure
at these companies,
which will give you a significant
advantage in your job search.
&gt;&gt; Kirsten is just one of the many
dedicated people here at Udacity
that you'll interact with
throughout the program.
You'll also have reviewers, mentors,
other students, career staff,
hiring partners, and of course,
Ryan and me, to help you along the way.
It's these people that will help
you make the most of your Udacity
experience, and so, on behalf of
all of us, welcome to the program.