Okay, so before we continue with other
algorithms, let's do a little aside.
Let's say we found ourselves
on top of a mountain.
Mount Errorest.
And our goal is to get to
the bottom of the mountain.
So what strategy can we use?
Well, we can do it step by step.
We look around us in all the possible
directions we can go and
find out which direction will
get us to descend the most.
In this case,
it's this direction over here.
So we take one step in that direction.
And then we restart the process.
We look around us, and see in which
directions we descend the most.
And take a step in that direction.
And we continue this process
until we descend the mountain.
This algorithm is called
gradient descent, and
we'll be using it extensively
in machine learning.
You can think of the mountain as
a problem you want to solve, and
the bottom of the mountain
as the solution.
And our process to solve
the problem is to take
tiny steps in the correct direction
that will get us to the solution.