Now we know how to get an output from a
simple neural network like the one shown
here.
We'd like to use the output to make
predictions, but how do we build this
network to make predictions without
knowing the correct weights before hand?
What we can is present it with
data that we know to be true
then set the model parameters,
the weights to match that data.
First we need some measure of
how bad our predictions are.
The obvious choice is to use
the difference between the true target
value, y, and the network output, y hat.
However, if the prediction is too high,
this error will be negative and
if their prediction is too low by the
same amount the error will be positive.
We'd rather treat these
errors the same to
make both cases positive
we'll just square the error.
You might be wondering why not
just take the absolute value.
One bit of using the square
is that it penalizes
outliers more than small errors.
Also squaring the error
makes the math nice later.
This is the error for
just one prediction though.
We'd rather like to know the error for
the entire dataset.
So we'll just sum up the errors for each
data record denoted by the sum over mu,
this u looking guy here.
Now we have the total error for
the network over the entire dataset.
And finally,
we'll add a one half in front
because it cleans up the math later.
This formulation is typically called
the sum of the squared errors.
SSE for short because well it is
Remember that y hat is the linear
combination of the weights and
inputs passed through
that activation function.
We can substitute it in here,
then we see that the error depends on
the weights, wi, and
the input values, xi.
As I said before the data records
are represented by the Greek letter mu.
You can think of the data as two
tables or arrays, or matrices,
whatever works for you.
One contains the input data, x, and
the other contains the targets, y.
Each record is one row here, so
mu equals 1 is the first row.
Then, to calculate the total error,
you're just scanning through the rows of
these arrays and calculating the SSE.
Then summing up all of those results.
The SSE is a measure of
our network's performance.
If it's high,
the network is making bad predictions.
If it's low,
the network is making good predictions.
So we want to make it
as small as possible.
Going forward, let's consider a simple
example with only one data record
to make it easier to understand
how we'll minimize the error.
For the simple network the SSE is
the true target minus the prediction,
y- y hat and squared and divided by 2.
Substituting for the prediction, you see
the error is a function of the weights.
The weights are the knobs we can use
to alter the network's predictions
which in turn affects the overall error.
Then our goal is to find weights
that minimize the error.
Here is a simple depiction of
the error with one weight.
Our goals is to find the weight
at the bottom of this bowl.
Starting at some random weight,
we want to make a step in
the direction towards the minimum.
This direction is the opposite
to the gradient, the slope.
If we take many steps,
always descending down a gradient.
Eventually the weight will find
the minimum of the error function and
this is gradient descent.
We want to update the weight, so
a new weight, wi, is the old weight,
wi plus this weight step, delta wi.
This Greek letter, delta,
typically signifies change.
The weight step is
proportional to the gradient,
the partial derivative of the error
with respect to each weight, wi.
We can add in an arbitrary scaling
parameter that allows us to set the size
of the gradient descent steps.
This is called the learning rate,
signified by the Greek letter eta.
Calculating the gradient here
requires multivariable calculus.
Which you might already know since
we're taking partial derivatives.
I wouldn't worry too much if you
don't understand what I'm doing here.
It's more important to understand
the concept of gradient descent and
the final result.
If you need a refresher, I suggest Khan
Academy multivariable calculus lessons,
which I'll link to for your convenience.
Writing out the gradient,
you get the partial derivative
with respect to the weights
of the squared error.
The network output, y hat,
is a function of the weights.
So what we have here is
a function of another function
that depends on the weights.
This requires using the chain
rule to calculate the derivative.
Here is a quick refresher
on the chain rule.
Say you want to take the derivative
of a function p with respect to z.
If p depends on another
function q that depends on z.
The chain rule says, you first take the
derivative of p with the respect to q,
then multiply it by the derivative
of q with the respect to z.
I like to envision this as
normal fractions, the d q's and
the denominator and numerator
cancel out, and you get back dpdz.
This relates to our problem because
we can set q to the error,
y- y hat and set p to the squared error.
And then we're taking
the derivative with respect to wi,
the derivative of p with respect
to q returns the error itself.
The 2 in the exponent drops down and
cancels out the 1/2.
Then we're left with the derivative
of the error with respect to wi.
The target value y doesn't depend
on the weights, but y hat does.
Using the Chain Rule again,
the minus sign comes out in front and
we're left with the partial
derivative of y hat.
If you remember, y hat is equal
to the activation function at h.
Where h is the linear combination
of the weights and input values.
Taking the derivative of y hat,
and again using the chain rule.
You get the derivative of
the activation function at h,
times the partial derivative
of the linear combination.
In the sum, there is only one
term that depends on each weight.
Writing this out for
weight one, you see that only the first
term with x1 depends on weight one.
Then the partial derivative of the sum
with respect to weight one is just x1.
All the other terms are zero,
then the partial derivative of this
sum with respect to wi is just xi.
Finally, putting all this together,
the gradient of the squared error
with respect to wi is
the negative of the error
times the derivative of the activation
function at h times the input value xi.
Then the weight step is a learning
rate eta times the error,
times the activation derivative,
times the input value.
For convenience, and to make things
easy later, we can define an error term,
lowercase delta, as the error times
the activation function derivative at h.
Then we can write our weight
update as wi equals wi
plus the learning rate times the error
term times xi is the value of input i.
You might be working with
multiple output units.
You can think of this as just stacking
the architecture from the single output
network but connecting the input
units to the new output units.
Now the total error would include
the error of each outputs sum together
The gradient descent step can be extended
to a network with multiple output.
By calculating an error term for
each output unit denoted
with the subscript j.
Next, I'll show you how to
translate this into codes.
So you can implement gradient descent in Python and Numpy