We saw before with the XOR perceptron
that adding a second layer of units
allows the model to find solutions
to linearly inseparable problems.
So here is an example of a multilayer
perceptron, with three input units,
one output unit, and
two units in the middle.
This middle layer is
called the hidden layer.
Calculating the output of this network
is the same as before, except that now,
the activations of the hidden layer are
used as the input to the output layer.
The input to the hidden
layer is the same as before.
It's these weights times the input
values plus some bias term.
And as before, again, you use
an activation function such as a sigmoid
to calculate the output
of the hidden layer.
The hidden layer activations
are passed to the output layer through
the second set of weights and
again use an activation function
to get the output of the network.
Stacking more and
more layers like this, helps the network
learn more complex patterns.
This is where deep learning gets
its name from, and what makes it so
powerful.
Deep stacks of hidden layers.