Now we're dealing with
multiple layers and
we'd still like to train
the network with gradient descent.
>From before, we know how to calculate
the error in the output node.
We can use this error with
gradient descent to train
the hidden to output weights.
But to train the input
to hidden weights,
we need to know the error caused
by the units in the hidden layer.
How do we find these errors to
use in the gradient descent step?
Before, we found the errors by taking
the derivative of the squared errors
which respect to the weights between
the input and output layers.
If we do that with a hidden layer, using
the chain rule, we find the error for
units there is proportional to
the error in the output layer
times the weight between the unit.
And this makes sense.
A unit with a stronger
connection to the output node,
is going to contribute more
error to the final output.
Here, you see the error
times the weights.
This is the same way you propagate
inputs through the network,
the inputs times the weights
between the layers.
Instead of propagating
the inputs forward,
you're propagating the error
backwards through the network.
Now, you can view this process
as flipping the network over and
using the error as the input.
This method is called backpropagation.
And this process works the same
when you add more layers.
You just keep propagating
the errors through the layers.
Backpropagation is fundamental
to how neural networks learn.
So it's really important
to understand this,
if you're going to be
building deep learning models