Well to help us out, we can see that
these points kind of form a line.
And we can draw the line
that best fits this data.
Now on this line, we can see that our
best guess for the price of the house is
this point here over the line,
which corresponds to $120,000.
So if you said $120,000,
that is correct.
This method is known
as linear regression.
You can think of linear regression as a
painter, who will look at your data and
draw the best fitting line through it.
Now you may be asking,
how do we find this line?
So let's try a small example.
Let's try to fit the best line that fits
through these three points over here.
Obviously best line is subjective, but
we'll find some line that works well.
Since we're pretending to be a computer,
we can't really eyeball the line.
So we're going to start by
drawing a random line and
seeing how bad this line is.
In order to see how bad this line is,
we calculate the error.
So we're going to look at the length of
the distances from the line to the three
points.
And we're going to say that the error
of this line is the sum of those
three lengths.
Now what we're going to do is
to move this line around and
see if we can reduce the error.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So, let's say we move in this direction.
And we calculate the error again.
It’s given by these yellow distances.
We add them up and realize that
we've just increase the error, so
that's not good.
Let's try moving in
the other direction then.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We move it and
again calculate the error.
It's given by the sum
of the green distances.
And we see that the errors smaller,
so we say, let's take that step.
If we continue doing this
procedure several times,
we'll always be decreasing the error,
and
we'll finally arrived to a good
solution in the form of this line.
This general procedure to minimize
the error, is known as gradient descent.
In real life, since we don't want to
deal with negative distance.
What we do, is instead of finding the
distances from the line to the points,
we actually have their squares.
This procedure is called least squares.
So we're back here on the summit
of Mount Errorest, and
we're trying to descent to the bottom.
Now in this context, the higher
we are the larger our error is.
So descending means reducing the error.
Now what do we do?
Well, we look at our surroundings and
try to figure out which
way we can descend more.
That's the equivalent of jiggling
the line around and looking for
the movement that reduces
the error the most.
So for example here,
this seems to be the direction
that makes it descend the most.
So we take a step in that direction.
That is the equivalent of moving
the line one step in the direction that
decreases the error the most.
In a way, removing the line
closer to the three points.
So now we've reduced our error and got
closer to the bottom of the mountain,
then we can start the procedure again.
Looking at our surroundings and deciding
in what direction we descend the most.
Or equivalently, in what direction
we get closer to the points.
Then we start the procedure again and
again, looking at our surroundings and
deciding in what direction we
descend the most, or equivalently,
in what direction we get
closer to the points.
What we just did, was reducing the error
until we find its minimum value,
which gives us the best line fit.