Now let's say we're the admissions
office at a university, and
we're trying to figure out
which students to admit.
We're going to admit them or reject
them based on two pieces of information,
an entrance test we provide them,
and their grades from school.
So for example, here we have student
one with scores of nine in test and
eight in the grades, and
that student got accepted.
We also have student two with
scores of three in the test and
four in the grades and
that student did not get accepted.
And then a new student comes in,
student three.
This person scores seven and six, and
the question is should we accept them or
not?
So to decide this, let's first put them
in a grid where the x axis represents
the score on the test and
the y axis represents the grades.
Here we can see that student one
would lie over here on the point with
coordinates nine, eight, and
student two would lie over here in the
point with coordinates three and four.
So in order to see if
we should accept or
reject student three,
we'll try to find the trend in the data.
For this we'll look at previous data in
the form of all students we've already
accepted or rejected.
It turns out that the previous
data looks like this.
The green dots represent students
that was previously accepted and
the red dots represent students
that was previously rejected.
Okay, so time for a quiz.
Based on this previous data do we
think student three gets accepted?
Yes or no?
Submit your answer below.