Once again we're in the fortunate
position to be able to bring
a world expert into the classroom.
Vincent Vanhoucke is the the principal
scientist of Google's deep learning
team, and he'll teach you the
fundamentals of deep neural networks.
&gt;&gt; Vincent will cover the jump from
machine learning to deep learning,
the architecture of multilayer
deep neural networks and
the concepts underpinning
convolutional neural networks.
A convolutional neural network is a
specialized type of deep neural network
that turns out to be particularly
important for self-driving cars.
At the end of the this section,
you'll use the TensorFlow deep
learning library to build your
own convolutional neural network.
&gt;&gt; Within the course, you'll see
optional assignments which are designed
to familiarize you with TensorFlow.
These assignments are a great
way to get more practice and
stand out to employers.
&gt;&gt; First things first, let's learn from
Vincent about how to take what you know
about machine learning and use it
as an entry point to deep learning.
We'll see you when you finish.