This entire course, I'm going to focus
on the problem of classification.
Classification is the task of taking
an input, like this letter, and
giving it a label that says this is a B.
The typical setting is that you have
a lot of examples, called the training
sets, that have already been sorted in
this is an A, this is a B, and so on.
Now here is a completely new example,
and
your goal is going to be to figure out
which of those classes it belongs to.
There is a lot more to machine
learning then just classification, but
classification, or
marginally prediction, is the central
building block of machine learning.
Once you know how to classify things,
it's very easy, for
example, to learn how to detect them or
to rank them.