So let’s get started training
a logistic classifier.
A logistic classifier is what’s
called the linear classifier,.
It takes the input, for example,
the pixels in an image, and
applies a linear function to them
to generate its predictions.
A linear function is just
a giant matrix multiplier.
It takes all the inputs as a big vector
that will denote x and multiplies
them with a matrix to generate its
predictions, one per output class.
Throughout we'll denote the inputs by x,
the weights by w and the bias term by b.
The weights of that matrix and the bias
is where the machine learning comes in.
We're going to train that model.
That means we're going to
try to find the values for
the weights and bias which are good
at performing those predictions.
How are we going to use those scores
to perform the classification?
Well, let's recap our task.
Each image that we have as an input can
have one and only one possible label.
So we're going to turn those
scores into probabilities.
We're going to want the probability of
the correct class to be very close to 1.
And the probability for
every other class to be close to 0.
The way to turn scores into
probabilities is to use a softmax
function.
Which I'll denote here by S.
This is what it looks like.
But beyond the formula what's
important to know about it
is that it can take any kind of scores
and turn them into proper probabilities.
Proper probabilities sum to 1 and they
will be large when the scores are large.
And small, when the scores
are comparatively smaller.
Scores, in the context
of logistic regression,
are often also called logits.