Many companies today,
have made deep learning a central part
of their mission learning toolkit.
Facebook, Baidu, Microsoft and Google,
are all using deep learning in their
products and
pushing the research forward.
It's easy to understand why, deep
learning shines wherever there is lots
of data and complex problems to solve.
And all these companies are facing
lots of complicated problems.
Understanding what's in an image,
to help you find it.
Or translating a document into
another language that you can speak.
This class will explore a continuum
of complexity from very simple models
to very large ones that you will
still be able to train in minutes
on your personal computer
to very elaborate tasks.
Predicting the meaning of words or
classifying images.
One of the nice things about deep
learning is it's really a family of
techniques that adapts to all sorts
of data and all sorts of problems.
All using a common infrastructure and
a common langauge to describe things.
When I began working
in machine learning,
I was doing research
on speech recognition.
Whenever I met someone
working on computer vision or
natural langauge processing, we had
very little in common to talk about.
We used different acronyms,
different techniques, and
collaboration was
pretty much impossible.
Deep learning really changed that.
The basic things that you will learn
in this class are applicable to
almost everything and will give you
a foundation that you can apply to many,
many different fields.
You'll be part of a fast growing
community of researchers, engineers and
data scientists who share a common,
very powerful set of tools.