You've already seen
some of these tricks.
I asked you to make your inputs zero
mean and equal variance earlier.
It's very important for SGD.
I also told you to initialize with
random weights that have relatively
small variance, same thing.
I'm going to talk about a few more
of those important tricks and
that should cover all you really need
to worry about to implement SGD.
The first one is momentum.
Remember that at each step, we're taking
a very small step in a random direction.
But on aggregate, those steps take
us towards the minimum of the loss.
We can take advantage of
the knowledge that we've accumulated
from previous steps about
where we should be headed.
A cheap way to do that is to keep
a running average of the gradients and
to use that running average instead
of the direction of the current
batch of the data.
This momentum technique works very well
and often leads to better convergence.
The second one is learning rate decay.
Remember, when replacing radiant
decent with SGD, I said that we were
going to take smaller,
noisier steps towards our objective.
How small should that step be?
That's a whole area of research,
as well.
One thing that's always the case,
however is that it's beneficial to make
that step smaller and
smaller as you train.
Some like to apply an exponential
decay to their learning rate.
Some like to make it smaller every
time the loss reaches a plateau.
There are lots of ways to go about it,
but
lowering it over time is
the key thing to remember.
[BLANK_AUDIO]