Learning rate training
can be very strange.
For example, you might think that
using a higher learning rate
means that you learn more or that you
learn faster, that's just not true.
In fact, you can often take a model,
lower the learning rate and
get to a better model faster.
It gets even worse.
You might be tempted to look at
the curve that shows the loss
over time to see how quickly you learn.
Here the higher learning
rate starts faster but
then it plateaus when the lower learning
rate keeps on going and gets better.
It is a very familiar picture for
anyone who's trained neural networks.
Never trust how quickly you learn,
it has often little to do
with how well you train.
This is where SGD gets its
reputation for being Black Magic.
You have many, many hyperparameters
that you could play with.
Initialization parameters,
learning rate parameters, decay,
momentum and you have to get them right.
In practice, it's not that bad but if
you have to remember just one thing is
that when things don't work, always
try to lower your learning rate first.
There are lots of good solutions for
small models.
But sadly, none that's completely
satisfactory, so far, for
the very large models that
we really care about.
I mentioned one approach called ADAGRAD
that makes things a little bit easier.
ADAGRAD is a modification of SGD
which implicitly does momentum and
learning rate decay for you.
Using ADAGRAD, often makes learning
less sensitive to hyperparameters.
[BLANK_AUDIO]